Gerardo Ramírez /

Senior Associate

Practice Area:
Public, Regulatory
and Administrative Law

gerardo.ramirez@ocl.cl

Gerardo has dedicated his professional career to Public and Regulatory Law and he has been counsel in administrative proceedings, in municipal, environmental, aquacultural, educational and other matters, especially those involving penalties. He has also counseled legislators in bills of law on television regulation and freedom of expression.

WORK HISTORY

2017 - present / Ovalle Consejeros Legales

2014 - 2017 / Office of the Government Chief of Staff

2013 - 2014 / Environmental Commission of Chile

EXPERIENCE

- Drafting and processing of the bill of law to modify the National Television Channel of Chile and create an educational and cultural over-the-air broadcast channel.
- Implementation of the Environmental Complaint Section of the Environmental Commission.

EDUCATION

Master in Regulatory Law, Pontifical Catholic University of Chile, 2017.

Specialization Course in Telecommunications and Audiovisual

Media Regulation under a scholarship from the Inter-American

Telecommunication Commission of the OAS and the Chilean Agency for International Cooperation and Development, Blas Pascal University, 2015.

B.A. in Legal and Social Sciences, University of Chile. Admissions: 2013.

PUBLICATIONS

- "Public television and its regulatory role. A supposition for freedom of expression." Editorial Hammurabi. 2019.
- Co-author: "State, Communication and Advertising. The dissemination of public policies and their considerations, and constitutional, legal and budgetary limitations." Thomson Reuters. 2018.
- Co-author "Communication and dissemination of government public policies. Constitutional, legal and budgetary considerations." Public Law Review (2016), second semester, School of Law, University of Chile.

LANGUAGES

Spanish and English

LINKEDIN

www.linkedin.com/in/gerardoramirezgonzalez